Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 17.09.05 20:34:17
\h\h漫威电影 工\h作\h室
________
\h\h漫威电影
卡西流斯大师
Master kaecilius.
那项仪式只会带给你懊悔
That ritual will bring you only sorrow.
伪君子
Hypocrite!
猜歌大挑战 比利
Challenge round, Billy.
拜托 比利 你太小看我了
Come on, Billy, you've got to be messing with me.
并没有 医生
No, doctor.
《如沐春风》 恰克曼裘尼 1977年
Feels so good, Chuck mangione, 1977.
比利 你明明说这次会很难
Honestly, Billy, you said this one would be hard.
- 哈！是1978年 - 不对 比利
-Ha! It's 1978. -No, Billy.
《如沐春风》在1978年登上排行榜
While feels so good may have charted in 1978...
专辑却是在1977年12月发行的
The album was released in December of 1977.
维基百科说是19…
-No. Wikipedia says it's a nineteen... -Check again.
再查一次
你干嘛记这些没用的资讯？
Where do you store all this useless information?
没用？
Useless?
他光吹富鲁格号就登上排行前十名
The man charted a top 10 hit with a flugelhorn.
哪一年 比利？
Status, Billy?
1977年
1977.
- 老是答对 - 我恨你
-Oh, please. -I hate you.
如沐春风 是吧？
Feels so good, doesn't it?
我来接手 史蒂芬
I got this, Stephen.
你任务完成了 走吧 我们来缝合
You've done your bit. Go ahead. We'll close up.
什么状况？
What is it?
枪伤
GSW.
你竟然能让他活着
It's amazing you kept him alive.
呼吸暂停 脑干检验失败
Apneic, failed the brain stem test...
呼吸暂停反射
And the apnea reflex test.
我应该找到问题了 帕默医师
I think I found the problem, doctor Palmer.
你把一颗子弹留在他头里
You left a bullet in his head.
谢谢 它打在延脑上
Thanks. It's impinging on the medulla.
我需要专家 尼克诊断脑死
I needed a specialist. Nic diagnosed brain death.
我觉得不太对劲
Something about that doesn't feel right to me.
我们快过去
We have to run.
魏医师
Doctor west.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing? Hey.
摘除器官 他是捐赠者
Organ harvest. He's a donor.
先别急 我没有同意
Slow down. I did not agree to that.
我不需要你同意 已经宣布脑死了
I don't need you to. We've already called brain death.
还有救 得帮他切除枕下颅骨
Prematurely.
We need to get him prepped for sub-occipital craniotomy.
我不会让你帮死人开刀
Not gonna let you operate on a dead man.
你看到什么？
What do you see?
- 子弹？ - 一颗完美的子弹
-A bullet? -A perfect bullet.
它经过硬化处理 铅锑合金可使子弹硬化
It's been hardened. You harden a bullet by alloying lead with antimony.
它是有毒金属 已直接溶入脊髓液
A toxic metal. And that's leeched directly into the cerebral spinal fluid.
快速击中 中枢神经系统停摆
Rapid onset central nervous system shutdown.
我们该走了
We gotta go.
病人还没死 但有生命危险
The patient's not dead, but he is dying. Still want to harvest his organs?
还想摘他的器官吗？
- 我协助你 - 不用
-I'll assist you. -No.
帕默医师会帮我
Doctor Palmer will assist me.
谢谢
Thank you.
手术影像导航 快
Image guidance, stat.
来不及了
We don't have time for that.
你不能徒手进行
You can't do it freehand.
可以 就这么办
I can and I will.
现在不是耍帅的时候 史传奇
This isn't a time for showing off, strange.
十分钟前
How about 10 minutes ago
你乱报死亡时间怎么说？
when you called the wrong time of death?
脑神经完整无损
Cranial nerves intact.
魏医师 盖住你的手表
Doctor west, cover your watch.
你没必要在大家面前羞辱他
You know, you didn't have to humiliate him in front of everyone.
我也没必要救他的病人
I didn't have to save his patient, either.
但我有时就是手痒
But I sometimes just can't help myself.
尼克是个好医生
Nic is a great doctor.
是你来找我的
You came to me.
对 我需要第二意见
Yeah, well, I needed a second opinion.
你已经有了第二意见
You had a second opinion. What you needed was a competent one.
你需要的是高手
那你更该来当我的神经外科顾问
Well, all the more reason why you should be my neurosurgeon on call.
你可以救更多的人
You could make such a difference.
我不能在你的屠宰场工作
I can't work in your butcher shop.
我连接横切脊髓
I'm fusing transected spinal cords.
刺激中枢神经系统的神经生成
I'm stimulating neurogenesis in the central nervous system.
这项研究未来能救成千上万的人
The work I'm doing is gonna save thousands for years to come.
在急诊室只能救被枪击的醉汉
In er, you get to save one drunk idiot with a gun.
你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
我们在急诊室只是救人
In er, we're only saving lives.
没有名望 也没人来采访
There's no fame, there's no CNN interviews.
看来我只好将就用尼克了
I guess I'll just have to stick with nic.
等一下
Wait a minute. You're not... You guys aren't...
你没有…你们该不会…
什么？
What?
炮友？抱歉 我以为我够含蓄了
Sleeping together? Sorry, I thought that was implicit in my disgust.
一点也不含蓄
Explicit, actually.
我才不来办公室恋情那一套
No, I have a very strict rule against dating colleagues.
是吗？
-Oh, really? -I call it the "strange policy."
这叫史传奇原则
赞 我的名字成了专有名词
Good, I'm glad something's named after me.
我发明了椎板切除术
I invented a laminectomy procedure.
却没人想叫它史传奇手术
And yet, somehow
no one seems to want to call it the "strange technique."
那是我们一起发明的
We invented that technique.
总之 你的原则让我受宠若惊
Regardless, I'm very flattered by your policy.
今晚我要在神经外科学会晚宴演讲
I'm talking tonight at a neurological society dinner.
跟我一起去吧
Come with me.
又是演讲约会？
Another speaking engagement?
真浪漫
So romantic.
你以前很喜欢陪我一起去的
You used to love coming to those things with me.
我们玩得很开心
We had fun together.
不 是你很开心
No! You had fun.
那与我们无关 重点在你身上
They weren't about us, they were about you.
重点不只在我
Not only about me.
史蒂芬 任何事的重点都在你身上
Stephen. Everything is about you.
也许我们可以联名
Maybe we could hyphenate.
史传奇帕默手术
Strange-Palmer technique.
帕默史传奇
Palmer-strange.
比利
Billy.
什么状况？
What have you got for me?
35岁空军上校
I've got a 35-year-old air force colonel...
穿着某种实验性盔甲时撞碎了脊椎
Crushed his lower spine in some kind of experimental armor.
脊椎中间破裂
Mid-thoracic burst fracture.
我可以帮忙
Yeah, well I could help...
但别的医生也可以
But so could 50 other people.
帮我找值得花时间的病人
Find me something worth my time.
68岁女性罹患晚期脑干胶质瘤
I have a 68-year-old female with an advanced brain stem glioma.
你想破坏我的完美纪录吗？
Yeah, you want me to screw up my perfect record?
想得美
Definitely not.
不然22岁女性
How about a 22-year-old female...
脑中有电子植入装置控制精神分裂
With an electronic implant in her brain to control schizophrenia...
遭到雷击
Struck by lightning?
听起来有点意思
That does sound interesting.
麻烦传给我…
Can you send me the...
收到了
Got it.
嘿
Hey.
没事 你会好起来的
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
他们做了什么？
What did they do?
他们出动直升机去救你
They rushed you in a chopper.
不过花了一点时间才找到你
But it took a little while to find you.
你困在车子里 错过了神经受损的黄金救援时间
The golden hours for nerve damage went by while you were in the car.
他们做了什么？
What did they do?
骨头里装了11根不锈钢钉
11 stainless steel pins in the bones.
多处韧带断裂
Multiple torn ligaments...
双手神经严重受损
Severe nerve damage in both hands.
你在手术台上躺了11小时
You were on the table for 11 hours.
你看这些固定器
Look at these fixators.
谁都不可能做得更好
No one could have done better.
我可以做得更好
I could have done better.
不
No.
给你身体一些时间复原
Give your body time to heal.
你毁了我
You've ruined me.
我要多久才能…
-How long until I can take... -Doctor strange.
史传奇医师
Those tissues are still healing.
那些组织还在复原中
那就加快速度
So, speed it up.
经由肱动脉将支架装在桡动脉里
Pass a stent down the brachial artery into the radial artery.
也许可以
It's possible.
昂贵的实验性手术 但有可能成功
Experimental and expensive, but possible.
只要有可能就好
All I need is possible.
抬起来
Up.
让我看到你有用力
Show me your strength.
这样没用
This is useless.
才怪 你做得到
It's not useless, man. You can do this.
那回答我 大学毕业生
All right, answer me this, bachelor's degree.
你知道谁神经受损这么严重
Have you ever known anyone with nerve damage this severe
做了复健
to do this...
然后完全康复？
And actually recover?
有一个男的
One guy, yeah.
在工厂发生意外 背部受伤
Factory accident, broke his back...
身体瘫痪 腿部萎缩
Paralyzed, his leg wasted away.
推轮椅造成肩膀疼痛
He had pain in his shoulder, from the wheelchair.
一周来三次
He came in three times a week. Then one day he stopped coming.
有一天就不来了
我以为他死了
I thought he was dead.
几年后 他在街上跟我擦身而过
A few years later, he walked past me on the street.
- 用走的？ - 对 用走的
-Walked? -Yeah, walked.
鬼扯 拿他病历给我看
Bullshit. Show me his file.
找病历要一点时间
It'll take me a while to pull the files from the archive.
不过为了让你这臭屁王心服口服
But if it proves your arrogant ass wrong...
值得
Worth it.
我拜读你所有的研究
I looked at all your research...
看过你寄的论文
I read all the papers you've sent.
那不可能成功的
It's not gonna work.
我想你不明白…
I don't think you realize...
受损有多严重 是这样的…
How severe the damages are.
最好的办法都失败了
-Here's the thing... -The best have tried and failed.
我了解 听我说
I understand. Here's the thing.
你要我做的事不可能成功 史蒂芬
What you want from me is impossible, Stephen.
别这样
Come on.
我也得考虑自己的名声
I've got my own reputation to consider.
- 艾提安 等等 - 我爱莫能助
-Etienne, wait. No. -I can't help you.
不 等一下
No, no, wait!
嘿
Hey!
他不答应
He won't do it.
他根本是蒙古大夫
He's a hack.
东京有一种新手术
There is a new procedure in Tokyo.
他们培养捐赠者的干细胞
They culture donor stem cells...
然后用3D列印细胞生长支架
And then harvesting them and then 3D printing a scaffold.
如果我能凑到钱…
If I could get a loan together...
史蒂芬
Stephen.
借20万就好
A small loan, just $200,000.
你一直都很会赚钱 花钱也不手软
You've always spent money as fast as you could make it...
但现在你根本没有钱继续这样花了
But now you're spending money you don't even have.
或许该考虑就此打住了
Maybe it's time to consider stopping.
怎么可以就此打住
No, now is exactly the time not to stop...
你没看到我根本没有好转吗
Because, you see, I'm not getting any better!
这已经无关医疗
But this isn't medicine anymore.
你失心疯了
This is mania.
有些事就是无力回天
Some things just can't be fixed.
- 不能工作… - 日子还是要过
-Life without my work... -Is still life.
这不是世界末日
This isn't the end.
人生有意义的事还很多
There are other things that can give your life meaning.
什么？你吗？
Like what? Like you?
请你道歉
This is the part where you apologize.
请你离开
This is the part where you leave.
好 我不忍心看你这样下去
Fine, I can't watch you do this to yourself anymore.
让你太难受了？
Too difficult for you, is it?
对 没错
Yes, it is.
看你这样折磨自己我心都碎了
It breaks my heart to see you this way.
- 不 别可怜我 - 我不是可怜你
-No, don't pity me. -I'm not pitying you.
是吗？那你带起司和酒来
Oh, yeah? Then what are you doing here...
一副老朋友要野餐的样子是干嘛？
Bringing cheese and wine like we're old friends going for a picnic?
我们不是朋友 克莉丝汀
We are not friends, Christine.
以前也算不上情侣
We were barely lovers.
你就是喜欢悲伤的故事 对吧？
But you just love a sob story, don't you?
我在你眼中是那么回事吗？
Is that what I am to you now?
可怜的史蒂芬史传奇 令人同情
"Poor Stephen strange, charity case."
他终于需要我了
"He finally needs me."
又一个需要你拯救的人渣
Another dreg of humanity for you to work on.
把他治好 让他回到社会上
Patch him up and send him back into the world...
心脏还能跳就好
Heart's just humming.
你超有爱心 对不对？
You care so much, don't you?
再见 史蒂芬
Goodbye, Stephen.
史蒂芬\h\h史传奇
报\h告
\clip(m 81 36 l 89 113 62 123 53 44) 告诉 过你 了！
潘柏恩·J 2014年12月9日 大都会综合医院
快传球 对
All the way. Here we go.
屡试不爽
Let's go! All day! All day!
水啦！屡试不爽
Yeah! All day.
拜托 有没有在比赛？
Come on, man! Where's the competition?
只剩一张嘴
Talk a lot.
强纳森潘柏恩
Jonathan pangborn...
C7、C8脊椎完全受损
C7-c8 spinal cord injury, complete.
你是谁？
-Who are you? -Paralyzed from the mid-chest down.
中胸以下瘫痪
Partial paralysis in both hands.
双手部分瘫痪
- 我不认识你 - 我是史蒂芬史传奇
-I don't know you. -I'm Stephen strange.
神经外科医师 以前啦
I'm a neurosurgeon. Was a neurosurgeon.
其实我认识你
Actually, you know what, man, i do know you.
我去过你门诊 你不肯帮我看
I came to your office once. You refused to see me.
你的助理不让我见你
I never got past your assistant.
当时你无法治疗
You were untreatable.
反正对你没好处 是吧？
No glory for you in that, right?
你竟然奇蹟式地完全恢复
You came back from a place there's no way back from.
我也想回到以前的自己
I'm trying to find my own way back.
潘柏恩 打不打？
Pangborn, are you in or you out?
好
All right.
我本来已经放弃我的身体了
I'd given up on my body.
我想既然只剩下脑袋
I thought my mind's the only thing i have left...
我至少应该设法提升它的能力
I should at least try to elevate that.
所以我和心灵导师
So, I sat with gurus...
以及神圣之女一起钻研
And sacred women.
有陌生人带我到山上见圣者
Strangers carried me to mountaintops to see holy men.
最后…
And finally...
我找到了我的导师
I found my teacher.
我的心智获得提升
And my mind was elevated...
性灵更加深化
And my spirit deepened.
不知不觉中…
And somehow...
你的身体也痊愈了
Your body healed.
是
Yes.
那里有更深奥的秘密可以学习
There were deeper secrets to learn there...
但我没有力气吸收它们
But I didn't have the strength to receive them.
我选择带着自己复原的奇蹟回家
I chose to settle for my miracle and I came back home.
你要找的地方叫卡玛泰姬
The place you're looking for is called kamar-taj.
但是付出的代价很高
But the cost there is high.
多少钱？
How much?
我讲的不是钱
I'm not talking about money.
祝你好运
Good luck.
打球 传过来
Let's ball. All right, ball up!
加德满都，尼泊尔
卡玛泰姬？
Kamar-taj?
知道卡玛泰姬在哪里吗？
You know where kamar-taj is?
■ 喜马拉雅治疗所！ \h找到 安宁！ \h找到 自我！
■
喜马拉雅治疗所！ \h找到 安宁！ \h找到 自我！
卡玛泰姬？
Kamar-taj?
卡玛泰姬
Kamar-taj.
好吧
Okay.
兄弟 我身上没钱
Look, guys, I don't have any money.
手表
Your watch.
别这样 我只剩下这个
No, please. It's all I have left.
你的手表
Your watch.
好吧
All right.
你在找卡玛泰姬
You're looking for kamar-taj.
真的吗？
Really?
确定是这里吗？
Sure we got the right place?
那边比较像卡玛泰姬
That one looks a little more kamar-tajey.
我曾经跟你一样
I once stood in your place.
目中无人
And I, too, was disrespectful.
方便给你一点建议吗？
So, might I offer you some advice?
放下你所有的自以为是
Forget everything you think you know.
好吧
All right.
我们导师的至圣所
The sanctuary of our teacher.
古一
The ancient one.
古一？
The ancient one? What's his real name?
他的本名呢？
对
Right.
放下我所有的自以为是 抱歉
Forget everything I think I know. Sorry.
谢谢你…
Thank you for...
真特别
Okay, that's a thing.
谢谢你…
Thank you for...
你好
Hello.
谢谢
Thank you.
And thank you.
谢谢你…
Thank you...
古一 愿意见我
Ancient one, for seeing me.
别客气
You're very welcome.
古一
The ancient one.
谢谢莫度大师 谢谢哈密尔大师
Thank you, master mordo. Thank you, master hamir.
史传奇先生
Mr. strange.
其实我是医生
Doctor, actually.
不 再也不是了
No, not anymore, surely.
那不正是你来的原因吗？
Isn't that why you're here?
你经历了多次手术
You've undergone many procedures.
七次 对不对？ 对
Seven, right?
Yeah.
好茶
It's good tea.
是
Yes.
你是不是治好一个叫潘柏恩的
Did you heal a man named pangborn?
一个瘫痪的男子？
A paralyzed man?
可以这么说
In a way.
你让他又可以走路
You helped him to walk again.
是
Yes.
你如何治愈C7跟C8脊椎的伤？
How did you correct a complete c7-c8 spinal cord injury?
我没有治好他
I didn't correct it.
他不能走路
He couldn't walk.
我让他相信他能走
I convinced him that he could.
你是说那是身心症？
You're not suggesting it was psychosomatic?
当你重新接上受损的神经
When you reattach a severed nerve...
让它复原的是你还是身体？
Is it you who heals it back together or the body?
是细胞
It's the cells.
细胞只是接受指示
The cells are only programmed...
以非常特殊的方式再度聚合
To put themselves back together in very specific ways.
对
Right.
如果我告诉你 你的身体能被说服
What if I told you that your own body could be convinced...
以各种方式自行修复呢？
To put itself back together in all sorts of ways?
你说的是细胞再生
You're talking about cellular regeneration.
那是非常先进的医学技术
That's bleeding edge medical tech.
那是你在这里工作的原因吗？
Is that why you're working here?
不受卫生组织管理？
Without a governing medical board?
你的疗法到底有多先进？
Just how experimental is your treatment?
相当了不起
Quite.
所以你研发出一种方法
So, you've figured out a way...
让神经细胞重新编排 然后自愈？
To reprogram nerve cells to self-heal?
不 史传奇先生
No, Mr. strange.
我知道如何重置心灵
I know how to reorient the spirit...
来更有效地疗愈身体
To better heal the body.
- 用心灵来治疗身体？ - 没错
-The spirit to heal the body? -That's right.
好吧
No. All right.
那要怎么进行？
How do we do that?
从哪里开始？
Where do we start?
- 不喜欢这张图吗？ - 不是
-Don't like that map? -Oh, no.
它很棒 只是我以前…
It's really good. It's just, I've seen it before...
在礼品店看过
In gift shops.
那这张呢？
And what about this one?
- 针灸 太好了 - 是吗？
-Acupuncture, great. -Yeah?
这张呢？
What about that one?
给我看磁振造影扫描 我不敢相信
Showing me an mri scan. I do not believe this.
画这些图的人
Each of those maps was drawn up by someone...
都只能看到部分 见树不见林
Who could see in part, but not the whole.
我花光积蓄 买单程机票过来
I spent my last dollar getting here, one-way ticket...
你却大谈用意志力治疗？
And you're talking to me about healing through belief?
你是个坐井观天的人
You're a man looking at the world through a keyhole.
穷尽一生想扩展眼界
You've spent your whole life trying to widen that keyhole...
开拓视野 增广见闻
To see more, to know more.
现在你听到眼界真能被扩大
Now, on hearing that it can be widened...
只是用超乎想像的方法
In ways you can't imagine...
你又拒绝那种可能性
You reject the possibility.
不 那是因为我不相信…
No, I reject it because I do not believe in fairy tales...
脉轮或能量之类的神话
About chakras or energy...
也不相信信仰的力量
Or the power of belief.
根本没有灵魂这种东西
There is no such thing as spirit!
人类是由物质所构成的 没有别的
We are made of matter...
你只不过是冰冷宇宙中
And nothing more.
You're just another tiny, momentary speck
另一粒无足轻重的微尘
within an indifferent universe.
你太小看自己了
You think too little of yourself.
你以为你看透我了吗？并没有
You think you see through me, do you? Well, you don't.
可是我却看透了你
But I see through you!
你刚刚对我做了什么？
What did you just do to me?
我把你的灵体推出肉体
I pushed your astral form out of your physical form.
茶里加了什么？
What's in that tea?
魔菇？迷幻药？
Psilocybin? LSD?
只是一般的茶
It's just tea...
加了点蜂蜜
With a little honey.
刚刚发生什么事？
What just happened?
刚刚你短暂进入了星灵界
For a moment, you entered the astral dimension.
什么？
The what?
一个灵魂脱离肉体的地方
A place where the soul exists apart from the body.
你为何这样对我？
Why are you doing this to me?
让你知道自己有多么无知
To show you just how much you don't know.
睁开眼睛
Open your eye.
靠！
Oh, shit!
天啊 不…
Oh, god! Oh, god, no!
不…
No, no, no!
发生什么事？
What's happening?
这不是真的
This isn't real!
他的心跳快到可能有危险
His heart rate is getting dangerously high.
我觉得他看起来还好
He looks all right to me.
你自以为明白世界的运行之道
You think you know how the world works?
自以为你所知的物质宇宙就是一切
You think that this material universe is all there is?
何谓真实？
What is real?
超越感官之外还有什么秘密？
What mysteries lie beyond the reach of your senses?
在存在的根源
At the root of existence...
性灵与物质交会
Mind and matter meet.
思想形塑现实
Thoughts shape reality.
宇宙之外还有无限个宇宙
This universe is only one of an infinite number.
没有尽头的无限世界
Worlds without end.
有的仁慈 孕育生命
Some benevolent and life giving.
有的充满恶意与饥渴
Others filled with malice and hunger.
在那些黑暗之处
Dark places...
比时间更古老的力量虎视眈眈
Where powers older than time lie ravenous...
蛰伏等待
And waiting.
在这多重宇宙里 你是谁 史传奇先生？
Who are you in this vast multiverse, Mr. strange?
这些你在礼品店里看过了吗？
Have you seen that before in a gift shop?
教我
Teach me.
不
No.
No!
不…
No, no, no!
不
No!
开门 求求你
Open the door! Please!
谢谢各位大师
Thank you, masters.
你觉得我不该赶他走？
You think I was wrong to cast him out?
五小时后 他还会在门口
5 hours later, he's still on your doorstep.
他很顽强
There's a strength to him.
固执、自大、野心
Stubbornness, arrogance, ambition. I've seen it all before.
我全都见过
他让你想起卡西流斯？
He reminds you of kaecilius?
我不能带领另一个天赋异禀的学生
I cannot lead another gifted student to power...
获得力量却坠入邪恶深渊
Only to lose him to the darkness.
我并没有掉进去
You didn't lose me.
我想获得击退敌人的能力
I wanted the power to defeat my enemies.
你赋予我战胜心魔的力量
You gave me the power to defeat my demons.
生活在自然法则里的力量
And to live within the natural law.
心魔始终不曾远离我们 莫度
We never lose our demons, mordo.
我们只是学会与它们共处
We only learn to live above them.
遗失的书页还在卡西流斯手上
Kaecilius still has the stolen pages.
一旦他破解了内容 就有可能…
If he deciphers them, he could bring ruin...
将毁灭降临世界
Upon us all.
未来恐怕有一场腥风血雨
There may be dark days ahead.
或许卡玛泰姬用得上史传奇这种人
Perhaps kamar-taj could use a man like strange.
不要拒我于门外
Don't shut me out.
我无处可去
I haven't got anywhere else to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
沐浴
Bathe.
休息
Rest.
可以的话…
Meditate...
冥想
If you can.
古一会派人来叫你
The ancient one will send for you.
香巴拉
What's this? My mantra?
这是什么？我的梵咒吗？
无线网路的密码
The Wi-Fi password.
我们不是野蛮人好吗？
We're not savages.
● 时间会告诉你\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h 我有多么爱你\h\h\h\h\h --\h\h\h 克丽丝汀
神秘之术的语言
The language of the mystic arts...
与文明一样古老
Is as old as civilization.
古代的魔法师
The sorcerers of antiquity...
将这种语言称为咒语
Called the use of this language "spells."
如果这名词不够时髦
But if that word offends your modern sensibilities...
你可以称之为程式
You can call it a "program."
塑造现实的原始码
The source code that shapes reality.
我们驾驭…
We harness energy...
来自多重宇宙中其他次元的能量
Drawn from other dimensions of the multiverse...
施展咒语
To cast spells...
召唤防护屏障
To conjure shields...
和武器
And weapons...
创造神奇魔法
To make magic.
就算我手指比得出来
But even if my fingers could do that...
也只像在做外丹功而已
My hands would just be waving in the air.
我要如何达到你的境界？
How do I get from here to there?
你如何接上受损神经
How did you get to reattach severed nerves...
将脊椎一节一节装回去？
And put a human spine back together bone by bone?
多年的学习钻研与练习
Study and practice, years of it.
嗨
Hey.
史传奇先生
Mr. strange.
请叫我史蒂芬
Stephen, please.
你是？ 王
And you are?
王
Wong.
就一个字 王？
Just wong?
像爱黛儿那样？
Like Adele?
或者亚里斯多德
Or Aristotle.
史瑞克
Drake.
波诺
Bono.
阿姆
Eminem.
《幻日之书》
The book of the invisible sun.
《新天文学》
Astronomia Nova.
《统御法典》
Codex imperium.
《所罗门之钥》
Key of Solomon.
全都看完了？
You finished all of these?
对
Yup.
跟我来
Come with me.
好
All right.
这一区仅供大师使用
This section is for masters only...
但我有权决定其他人可否使用
But at my discretion, others may use it.
你应该从《箴言入门》开始
You should start with Maxim's primer.
你懂梵文吗？
How's your sanskrit?
我很会用谷歌翻译
I'm fluent in Google translate.
吠陀 早期的梵文
Vedic, classical sanskrit.
那些是什么？
What are those?
古一的私人藏书
The ancient one's private collection.
不准看吗？
So, they're forbidden?
卡玛泰姬的知识都不是禁忌
No knowledge in kamar-taj is forbidden.
除了某些特例
Only certain practices.
那些书太高深
Those books are far too advanced
唯有至尊魔法师才能领略
for anyone other than the sorcerer supreme.
这本书有几页不见了
This one's got pages missing.
那是《卡里欧斯卓之书》
That's the book of cagliostro.
关于时间的研究
A study of time.
有一种仪式被过去的一位大师偷走
One of the rituals was stolen by a former master.
狂热者 卡西流斯
The zealot, kaecilius.
他先把图书馆员吊起来
Just after he strung up the former librarian...
然后砍了他的头
And relieved him of his head.
现在我负责守护这些书
I am now the guardian of these books.
万一里面有一本又被偷走
So if a volume from this collection should be stolen again...
我一定会知道
I'd know it...
你还没出大门就会丢掉小命
And you'd be dead before you ever left the compound.
如果只是逾期未还呢？
What if it's just overdue?
有逾期罚款吗？会残废？
Any late fees I should know about? Maiming, perhaps?
以前人家都觉得我很幽默
People used to think that I was funny.
他们是你的下属吗？
Did they work for you?
好吧 很开心跟你聊天
All right. It's been lovely talking to you.
谢谢你借我这些书
Thank you for the books...
讲这么恐怖的故事
And for the horrifying story...
还有威胁我的性命
And for the threat upon my life.
我们将获得歼灭背叛者的力量
We will now receive the power to destroy the one who betrayed us.
背叛这个世界的人
The one who betrays the world.
我们召唤你 魔王
听到召唤
就请到我们的身边来
让我们看到你们的真面目
我们在召唤
再来
收
放
接
集中
触发
先到这儿
灵环的活用是秘术的关键
Mastery of the sling ring is essential to the mystic arts.
它们能让我们在多重宇宙中穿梭
They allow us to travel throughout the multiverse.
你们只需要专注
All you need to do is focus.
视觉化
Visualize.
在脑海中看见目的地
See the destination in your mind.
眼光超越眼前的世界
Look beyond the world in front of you.
想像每个细节
Imagine every detail.
画面越清晰 入口就越快…
The clearer the picture, the quicker and easier...
越容易出现
The gateway will come.
停
And stop.
我想与史传奇先生单独谈谈
I would like a moment alone with Mr. strange.
没问题
Of course.
我的手
My hands.
重点不在你的手
It's not about your hands.
怎么不是？
How is this not about my hands?
哈密尔大师
Master hamir.
谢谢你 哈密尔大师
Thank you, master hamir.
你无法让河流听命于你
You cannot beat a river into submission.
而必须臣服于它的水流
You have to surrender to its current...
借用它的力量
And use its power as your own.
靠伏首称臣来控制它？
I control it by surrendering control? That doesn't make any sense.
根本没道理
万物并非皆有道理 也非必有道理
Not everything does. Not everything has to.
你的才智让你成就傲人
Your intellect has taken you far in life...
但仅止于此
But it will take you no further.
伏首称臣吧 史蒂芬
Surrender, Stephen.
放下你的自我
Silence your ego...
力量就会油然而生
And your power will rise.
跟我来
Come with me.
等一下
Wait.
- 这是… - 圣母峰
-Is this... -Everest.
好美
Beautiful.
对 美呆了
Yeah, right, beautiful.
冷毙了 但很美
Freezing but beautiful.
在这种温度下
At this temperature...
一个人只能撑30分钟
A person can last for 30 minutes...
然后永久失去身体机能
Before suffering permanent loss of function.
好极了
Great.
不过两分钟就可能休克
But you'll likely go into shock within the first two.
什么？ 伏首称臣吧 史蒂芬
What?
不！
Surrender, Stephen.
No!
菜鸟的表现如何？
How's our new recruit?
等着瞧
We shall see.
马上就会看到
Any second now.
最好别再来一遍
No, not again.
或许我该…
Maybe I should...
史蒂芬
Stephen.
王
Wong.
你要什么 史传奇？
What do you want, strange?
灵魂出窍的书
Books on astral projection.
你还没准备好
You're not ready for that.
放马过来 碧昂丝
Try me, Beyoncé.
少来 你一定听过她
Oh, come on. You've heard of her.
她是流行天后耶
She's a huge star, right?
你这辈子笑过吗？
Do you ever laugh?
快点 拿书给我
Come on, just give me the book.
不行
No.
你曾经在这里
Once, in this room, you begged me to let you learn.
求我让你学习
现在我却听说你质疑每项课程
Now, I'm told you question every lesson...
宁可自学
Preferring to teach yourself.
你曾经在这里叫我睁开眼睛
Once, in this room, you told me to open my eye.
现在却又叫我盲目接受…
Now, I'm being told to blindly accept rules...
毫无道理的规定
That make no sense.
像是不准在图书馆里召唤入口？
Like the rule against conjuring a gateway in the library?
王打我小报告？
Wong told on me?
你的法术能力进步神速
You're advancing quickly with your sorcery skills.
需要安全的地方练习施咒
You need a safe space to practice your spells.
你正在镜次元里
You are now inside the mirror dimension...
它始终存在却无法察觉
Ever present but undetected.
现实世界不受这里所影响
The real world isn't affected by what happens here.
我们运用镜次元训练、监督
We use the mirror dimension to train, surveil...
有时将威胁困住
And sometimes to contain threats.
没有灵环被困在这里就惨了
You don't wanna be stuck in here without your sling ring.
慢着 抱歉 你刚说威胁？
Hold on. Sorry. What do you mean, "threats?"
学习无限的多重宇宙 也包括学习无限的危险
Learning of an infinite multiverse includes learning of infinite dangers.
要是我把你不知道的事都告诉你
If I told you everything else that you don't already know...
你会吓到逃走
You'd run from here in terror.
她到底有多老？
So just how ancient is she?
没有人知道至尊魔法师的年龄
No one knows the age of the sorcerer supreme.
只知道她是凯尔特人 从不谈她的过去
Only that she's Celtic and never talks about her past.
你追随她 连你都不知道？
You follow her, even though you don't know?
我知道她稳如泰山
I know she's steadfast...
却也难以预料
But unpredictable.
无情却又仁慈
Merciless, yet kind.
她造就了今天的我
She made me what I am.
相信你的导师
Trust your teacher...
不要迷失方向
And don't lose your way.
像卡西流斯那样？
Like kaecilius?
没错
That's right.
你认识他
You knew him.
他来找我们时
When he first came to us...
他失去了所有心爱的人
He'd lost everyone he ever loved.
他悲痛欲绝 想在秘术中寻找答案
He was a grieving, broken man
searching for answers in the mystic arts.
他是优秀的学生 却骄傲固执
A brilliant student, but he was proud, headstrong.
质疑古一 拒绝她的指导
He questioned the ancient one, rejected her teaching.
他离开了卡玛泰姬
He left kamar-taj.
门徒像绵羊般跟随他
His disciples followed him like sheep. Seduced by false doctrine.
受到错误教义的引诱
他偷走禁忌仪式 对吧？
And he stole the forbidden ritual, right?
对
Yes.
那仪式是做什么的？
What did it do?
不能再问了
No more questions.
那是什么？
What's that?
你又在问了
That's a question.
这是一个法器
This is a relic.
有的魔法太过强大
Some magic is too powerful to sustain...
所以我们将它灌输到物体中
So we imbue objects with it...
让法器代我们去承受
Allowing them to take the strain we cannot.
这是…
This is the staff...
生命法庭的权杖
Of the living tribunal.
有许多法器
There are many relics.
瓦图姆魔杖
The wand of watoomb.
伏特尔的拱靴
The vaulting boots of valtorr.
念起来真像顺口溜
Really just roll off the tongue, don't they?
我何时会有自己的法器？ 等你准备好的时候
When do I get my relic?
我想我准备好了
When you're ready.
那得由法器来决定
I think I'm ready.
You're ready when the relic decides you're ready.
现在…
For now...
召唤一项武器
Conjure a weapon.
好
All right.
尽力反击
Fight!
像生死交关那样拼命
Fight like your life depended on it.
因为有一天…
Because one day...
可能救你一命
It may.
克莉丝汀
克莉丝汀 我再写一封电子邮件给你
王？
Wong?
好
Okay.
首先 打开阿迦莫托之眼
"First, open the eye of agamotto."
好
All right.
天啊
Oh, my.
What if...
多玛暮
"Dormammu."
黑暗次元
"The dark dimension."
永生？
Eternal life?
住手
What the...
Stop!
破坏时间连续性是被严格禁止的
Tampering with continuum probabilities is forbidden.
我只是照书上的指示
I was just doing exactly what it said in the book.
书上说
What did the book say about the dangers of performing that ritual?
执行这仪式会有什么危险？
不知道 我还没看到那里
I don't know. I hadn't gotten to that part yet.
操控时间可能造成时间错位
Temporal manipulations can create branches in time.
导致次元入口失序
Unstable dimensional openings.
空间矛盾 时间不断循环
Spatial paradoxes! Time loops!
你想要永远重复
You wanna get stuck reliving the same moment
同一个时刻
over and over forever...
还是根本没存在过？
Or never having existed at all?
他们应该在咒语前面加上警语
Really should put the warnings before the spell.
好奇心会要人命的
Your curiosity could have gotten you killed.
你不是在操控时空连续性
You weren't manipulating the space-time continuum...
而是在破坏它
You were breaking it.
我们不能窜改自然法则
We do not tamper with natural law. We defend it.
而是要保护它
你到底怎么弄的？
How did you even do that?
你怎么看得懂它所需的长串咒语？
Where did you learn the litany of spells required to even understand it?
我过目不忘
I've got a photographic memory.
所以才能同时拿到 医师资格和博士学位
That's how I got my m.D. And ph.D. At the same time.
你刚刚所做的…
What you just did...
不只需要超强记忆力
Takes more than a good memory.
你天生就是秘术高手
You were born for the mystic arts.
但我的手还在抖
And yet my hands still shake.
只是暂时的
For now, yes.
不会这样一直下去吗？
Not forever?
我们又不是算命仙
We're not prophets.
你何时要跟我说我们的身分？
When are you gonna start telling me what we are?
复仇者联盟那样的英雄
While heroes like the avengers
保护世界对抗有形体的物质危险
protect the world from physical dangers...
我们魔法师则保护世界 对抗形而上的神秘威胁
We sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.
古一是这一代的
The ancient one is the latest in a long line of sorcerers supreme...
至尊魔法师
他们最早可追溯到 数千年前的秘术之父
Going back thousands of years to the father of the mystic arts...
伟大的阿迦莫托
The mighty agamotto.
他创造了你擅自借用的这个眼睛
Same sorcerer who created the eye you so recklessly borrowed.
阿迦莫托在能量之地 建立三座至圣所
Agamotto built three sanctums in places of power...
那些地方如今都是大城市
Where great cities now stand.
那道门通往香港至圣所
That door leads to the Hong Kong sanctum.
那道门通往纽约至圣所
That door to the New York sanctum.
那道通往伦敦至圣所
That one to the London sanctum.
这些至圣所…
Together...
共同在我们世界周围形成防护盾
The sanctums generate a protective shield around our world.
至圣所保护世界
The sanctums protect the world...
我们魔法师…
And we sorcerers...
保护至圣所
Protect the sanctums.
为了防范什么？
From what?
来自其他次元的威胁
Other dimensional beings that threaten our universe.
像是多玛暮
Like dormammu.
你怎么知道这名字？
Where did you learn that name?
我在《卡里欧斯卓之书》看到的 怎么了？
I just read it in the book of cagliostro. Why?
多玛暮住在黑暗次元
Dormammu dwells in the dark dimension.
超越时间
Beyond time.
他是宇宙征服者
He is the cosmic conqueror...
世界破坏者
The destroyer of worlds.
具有无穷力量
A being of infinite power and endless hunger...
不断想入侵每个宇宙
On a quest to invade every universe...
将所有世界纳入他的黑暗次元
And bring all worlds into his dark dimension.
他最渴望的就是地球
And he hungers for earth most of all.
卡西流斯偷走的那几页
The pages that kaecilius stole.
那仪式能联系多玛暮
A ritual to contact dormammu
从黑暗次元汲取力量
and draw power from the dark dimension.
好吧
Okay...
我退出
I'm out.
我来是为了治疗我的手
I came here to heal my hands.
不是打什么神秘战争
Not to fight in some mystical war.
伦敦
London.
卡西流斯
Kaecilius!
不！
No!
王？莫度？
Wong? Mordo?
177A 布里克街
有人在吗？
Hello?
丹尼尔 原来是你当上这座至圣所的大师
Daniel, I see they made you master of this sanctum.
知道那代表什么意思吗？
You know what that means?
你将为了保护它而死
That you'll die protecting it.
住手
Stop!
你在卡玛泰姬待多久了…先生？
How long have you been at kamar-taj, mister...
医生
Doctor.
达克特先生？
Mister doctor?
史传奇
It's strange.
现在是流行取怪名吗？
Maybe. Who am I to judge?
你根本不会用吧？
You don't know how to use that, do you?
什么？
What?
停
Stop it.
我叫你停下来
I said stop it.
这停不下来的 达克特先生
You cannot stop this, mister doctor.
我根本不知道“这”是什么
I don't even know what "this" is.
它是末日
It's the end...
也是开始
And the beginning.
无数次元逐渐减少 最后变成一个
The many becoming the few becoming the one.
你要再胡言乱语
If you're not gonna start making sense...
我就把这东西放回去
I'm just gonna have to put this thing back on.
告诉我 达克特先生
Tell me, mister doctor...
我是史蒂芬史传奇医生
My name is doctor Stephen strange.
- 你是医生？ - 对
-You are a doctor? -Yeah.
科学家
A scientist.
你了解自然法则
You understand the laws of nature.
万物皆会老化 皆会死去
All things age. All things die.
我们的太阳终将烧尽
In the end, our sun burns out.
我们的宇宙会变冷而毁灭
Our universe grows cold and perishes.
但是黑暗次元…
But the dark dimension...
它是个超越时间的地方
It's a place beyond time.
够了 我把这玩意放回去
That's it. I'm putting this thing back on.
这世界不见得要灭亡 医生
This world doesn't have to die, doctor.
这世界能找到适当的位置 跟其他许多世界
This world can take its rightful place alongside so many others...
构成独一宇宙
As part of the one.
伟大而美丽的独一宇宙
The great and beautiful one.
我们能够长生不老
We can all live forever.
是吗？
Really?
你从那个美丽乌托邦能得到什么？
What do you have to gain out of this new age dimensional utopia?
跟你一样
The same as you.
跟大家一样 生命 永生
The same as everyone. Life. Eternal life.
人们只想到善恶
People think in terms of good and evil...
其实时间才是我们真正的敌人
When really time is the true enemy of us all.
时间扼杀一切
Time kills everything.
那你杀的那些人呢？
What about the people you killed?
微不足道
Tiny.
冰冷宇宙中无足轻重的一粒微尘
Momentary specks within an indifferent universe.
对 你懂
Yes. You see.
你明白我们的所作所为
You see what we're doing.
这世界不该如此
The world is not what it ought to be.
人类渴望永恒
Humanity longs for the eternal...
渴望一个超越时间的世界 因为时间奴役了我们
For a world beyond time, because time is what enslaves us.
时间是一种羞辱
Time is an insult.
死亡是一种羞辱
Death is an insult.
医生
Doctor...
我们并不希望统治世界
We don't seek to rule this world.
我们希望拯救它
We seek to save it...
将它交给多玛暮 他是演化的终极目标
To hand it over to dormammu, who is the intent of all evolution...
所有生命存在的原因
The why of all existence.
至尊魔法师才会保护生命
The sorcerer supreme defends existence.
你为何来到卡玛泰姬 医生？
What was it that brought you to kamar-taj, doctor?
受到启蒙吗？
Was it enlightenment?
为了得到力量？
Power?
你是来被治愈的 跟我们都一样
You came to be healed, as did we all.
卡玛泰姬是个收破烂的地方
Kamar-taj is a place that collects broken things.
我们都期望能够痊愈
We all come with the promise of being healed...
古一却尽给我们一些魔术伎俩
And instead the ancient one gives us parlor tricks.
真正的法术她深藏不露
The real magic she keeps for herself.
你想过她怎么活这么久吗？
You ever wonder how she managed to live this long?
我在卡里欧斯卓之书看到那些仪式
I saw the rituals in the book of cagliostro.
所以你知道
So, you know.
那仪式能给我力量
The ritual gives me the power to overthrow the ancient one...
推翻古一
摧毁她的至圣所
And tear her sanctums down.
引入黑暗次元
To let the dark dimension in.
因为古一隐藏独占的法术
Because what the ancient one hoards, dormammu gives freely.
多玛暮却大方分享
永生
Life everlasting.
他不是世界的摧毁者
He's not the destroyer of worlds, doctor.
而是救世者
He's the savior of worlds.
不 怎么可能
No. I mean, come on.
看看你的脸
Look at your face.
多玛暮让你成为杀人凶手
Dormammu made you a murderer.
他的王国能有多美好？
Just how good can his kingdom be?
你觉得很好笑吗？
You think that's funny?
不是
No, not that.
好笑的是你的灵环不见了
What's funny is that you've lost your sling ring.
先生 需要帮忙吗？
Sir, can I help you?
帕默医师 她在哪？
Doctor Palmer, where is she?
- 先生 我们需要… - 她在哪？
-Sir. We need to get... -Where is she?
护理站
The nurse's station.
克莉丝汀
Christine!
史蒂芬？
Stephen?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
马上带我进手术室 你进来就好
Get me in an operating theater now. Just you.
快 我没时间了
Now! I haven't any time.
发生什么事？
What happened?
我被刺伤 心包填塞
I was stabbed. Cardiac tamponade.
你身上穿的是什么？
What are you wearing?
胸腔没有状况
Chest cavity is clear.
不 心包囊出血
No, the blood is in the pericardial sac.
不…
No, no, no.
史蒂芬？
Stephen?
天啊
Come on, come on.
心跳率过低
高一点
Just a little higher.
用针拜托小心点
Please be careful with the needle.
史蒂芬
Stephen?
我看到了什么？
What am I seeing?
我的灵体
My astral body.
你死了吗？
Are you dead?
不 但我快死了
No, Christine. But I am dying.
对
Right.
好吧
Yeah. All right.
好
Okay.
哇
Oh, wow.
我没见过这种伤口
I've never seen a wound like this.
你被什么刺伤？
What were you stabbed with?
不知道
I don't know.
我必须消失了
I'm gonna have to vanish now.
什么？
What?
让我活下去 好吗？
Keep me alive, will you?
好
Okay.
惨了
Oh, shit.
充电至200焦耳
Come on, come on.
史蒂芬 加油
Stephen, come on.
再来一次
Hit me again.
不要这样吓人
Stop doing that!
加强电流 再来一次
Up the voltage and hit me again.
不 你的心脏在跳了
No, your heart's beating!
动手就是了
Just do it!
天啊
Oh, my god.
选择电流强度：（焦耳）
充电至360焦耳
请勿碰触病患 按下电击按钮
天啊…
Oh, god! Oh, god!
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
好
Okay.
过了这么久
After all this time...
你突然出现在这里
You just show up here...
飞出自己的身体
Flying out of your body.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
对了 我也很想你
I missed you, too, by the way.
哈哈
Ha ha.
我写电邮给你 你都没回
I wrote you emails, but you never responded.
我干嘛回？
Why would I?
克莉丝汀 我真的非常抱歉
Christine, I am so, so sorry.
你说的都对
For all of it. You were right.
我是个大猪头 对你真的很坏
I was a complete asshole. I treated you so horribly.
你值得被好好珍惜
And you deserved so much more.
住口 你惊吓过度了
Stop. You're clearly in shock.
到底发生什么事？
What the hell is happening?
你到哪去了？
Where have you been?
西医对我束手无策
After western medicine failed me...
我往东方去 最后到了加德满都
I headed east, and I ended up in kathmandu.
加德满都？
Kathmandu?
对
Yeah.
像巴布席格那首歌？
Like the Bob seger song?
1975年 《美丽失败者》 A面
1975, beautiful loser, side a. Yeah.
我到了一个叫卡玛泰姬的地方
I went to a place called kamar-taj...
跟一个叫古一的人交谈
And I talked to someone called "the ancient one."
所以你加入邪教
So you joined a cult.
没有 不算是
No, I didn't. No, not exactly. No.
他们教我开发我不知道的力量
They did teach me to tap into powers that I never even knew existed.
听起来就像邪教
Yeah. That sounds like a cult.
那不是邪教
It's not a cult.
邪教信徒都这么说
That's what a cultist would say.
不
Oh, no.
等等 史蒂芬 你想干嘛？
Wait. Stephen, wait. What do you think you're doing?
邪教聚会快迟到了
I'm late for a cult meeting.
这实在太扯了
This is insane.
是啊
Yeah.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
你能跟我说实话吗？
Can you tell me the truth?
有个信奉某种古老形体的强大法师
A powerful sorcerer who gave himself over to an ancient entity...
他能改变物理法则 千方百计要杀我
Can bend the very laws of physics, tried very hard to kill me.
但我把他拴在格林威治村
But I left him chained up in greenwich village...
回到那里最快的办法 就是穿过我在清洁工具间
And the quickest way back there is through a dimensional gateway...
打开的异次元入口
That I opened up in the mop closet.
好吧 别告诉我
Okay. Don't tell me. Fine.
我真的该走了
Really do have to go.
喔
Yeah.
史传奇
Strange!
你没事
You're okay.
相较之下 我算没事
A relative term. But yeah, I'm okay.
魔浮斗篷
The cloak of levitation.
它找上了你
It came to you.
这可不容易
No minor feat.
它喜怒无常
It's a fickle thing.
他逃走了 卡西流斯？
He's escaped.
对
Kaecilius?
他能任意摺叠空间和物体
Yeah.
He can fold space and matter at will.
他能摺叠镜次元之外的物体
He folds matter outside the mirror dimension...
在现实世界里？
In the real world?
是
Yeah.
还有几个？ 两个
How many more?
我把其中一个困在沙漠里
Two.
I stranded one in the desert.
另一个呢？
And the other?
他的身体在走廊
His body's in the hall.
杜朗大师在门厅
Master drumm is in the foyer.
他被带回卡玛泰姬了
He's been taken back to kamar-taj.
伦敦至圣所沦陷了
The London sanctum has fallen.
现在只剩纽约和香港
Only New York and Hong Kong remain now...
保护我们不沦落到黑暗次元
To shield us from the dark dimension.
你让纽约至圣所躲过攻击
You defended the New York sanctum from attack.
如今它的大师出缺 需要再找一个
With its master gone, it needs another.
史传奇大师
Master strange.
不
No.
我是史传奇医师
It is doctor strange.
不是史传奇大师 不是史传奇先生
Not master strange. Not mister strange.
史传奇医师
Doctor strange.
我当上医生时曾发誓不伤害人
When I became a doctor, i swore an oath to do no harm.
我却杀了一个人
And I have just killed a man!
下不为例
I'm not doing that again.
我当医生是为了救人 不是杀人
I became a doctor to save lives, not take them.
你当医生只为了救一个人
You became a doctor to save one life above all others.
你自己
Your own.
你还是看穿我了 是吧？
Still seeing through me, are you?
我看到的东西没变 你过度膨胀的自我
I see what I've always seen: Your over-inflated ego.
你想回到那个以为 你能掌控一切的幻象
You want to go back to the delusion that you can control anything...
甚至死亡
Even death...
但谁都无法掌控死亡
Which no one can control.
连伟大的史传奇医师都没办法
Not even the great doctor Stephen strange.
连多玛暮也不能吗？
Not even dormammu?
他说我们能永生不死
He offers immortality.
多玛暮的生命来自我们怕死
It's our fear of death that gives dormammu life.
他靠那种能量而壮大
He feeds off it.
就像你靠他才壮大？
Like you feed off him?
你跟我谈掌控死亡？
You talk to me about controlling death?
我知道你的秘诀
I know how you do it.
我看过卡里欧斯卓之书上 遗失的仪式内容
I've seen the missing rituals from the book of cagliostro.
接下来说话当心点 医生
Measure your next words very carefully, doctor.
因为你不爽听？
Because you might not like them?
因为你根本不懂自己说出口的话
Because you may not know of what you speak.
他在说什么？
What is he talking about?
我在说她这么长寿 永生不老的原因
I'm talking about her long life, the source of her immortality.
她靠汲取黑暗次元的力量存活
She draws power from the dark dimension to stay alive.
并不是
That's not true.
我解析了那些仪式
I've seen the rituals. Worked them out.
我知道你如何办到
I know how you do it.
他们一旦重新整合
Once they regroup...
狂热者就会回来
The zealots will be back.
你需要外力协助
You'll need reinforcements.
她不是你所想的那样
She's not who you think she is.
你没有立场这么说
You don't have the right to say that.
你不知道她肩负着多大责任
You've no idea the responsibility that rests upon her shoulders.
对 我也不想知道
No, and I don't want to know.
你这懦夫
You're a coward.
因为我不是杀人凶手？
Because I'm not a killer?
这些狂热者会杀光我们
These zealots will snuff us all out...
你不能集中力量先歼灭他们吗？
And you can't muster the strength to snuff them first?
你以为我刚刚做了什么？
What do you think I just did?
你救了自己一命
You saved your own life!
然后又抱怨个不停
And then whined about it like a wounded dog.
难道你杀人像喝水一样简单？
You would have done it so easily?
你不知道我做过什么
You've no idea the things I've done.
没有错
And the answer is yes.
我杀人不眨眼
Without hesitation.
即使还有其他办法？
Even if there's another way?
没有其他办法
There is no other way.
你缺乏想像力
You lack imagination.
不 史蒂芬
No, Stephen.
是你没种
You lack a spine.
他们回来了
They're back.
我们得把他们解决掉
We have to end this.
动手
Now!
史传奇
Strange!
下来对抗他们
Get down here and fight!
不！
No!
镜次元
The mirror dimension.
你在这里无法影响现实世界
You can't affect the real world in here.
现在该笑的是谁？
Who's laughing now?
混蛋
Asshole.
是我
I am.
我拿到他的灵环了
I've got his sling ring. They can't escape, right?
他们逃不掉了吧？
快跑！
Run!
他们与黑暗次元的关联
Their connection to the dark dimension
使他们在镜次元中更强大
makes them more powerful in the mirror dimension.
他们无法影响现实世界 却还是能杀死我们
They can't affect the real world, but they can still kill us.
这样并不明智 反而是自杀
This wasn't cleverness. It was suicide!
众妙之门
太爆笑了
That is hilarious.
这完全是个错误
This was a mistake.
果然没错
It's true.
她确实从黑暗次元汲取法力
She does draw power from the dark dimension.
卡西流斯
Kaecilius.
我来找你时身心俱疲
I came to you broken...
彷徨无助
Lost, in need.
我把你当成导师 你却满口谎言
Trusted you to be my teacher, and you fed me lies.
我是想保护你
I tried to protect you.
不让我知道真相吗？ 不让你伤害自己
From the truth?
现在我有了新导师
From yourself.
I have a new teacher now.
多玛暮骗你
Dormammu deceives you.
你不知道他的真面目
You have no idea what he truly is.
他的永生不是天堂 而是苦难
His eternal life is not paradise, but torment.
骗人
Liar.
克莉丝汀
Christine!
开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding me?
天啊
Oh, my god.
不是心房颤动 她心肌顿抑
It's not fibrillation. She has a stunned myocardium.
- 神经引起的？ - 对
-Neurogenic? -Yes.
谁去拿棉花棒
Someone get the swabs.
尼克
Nic?
我们得降低她的脑压
We need to relieve the pressure on her brain.
她心跳率继续下降
She's still dropping.
她快不行了
-We're losing her! -We need to increase her oxygen!
增加她的氧气
我需要急救车
-I need a crash cart! -Her pupils have dilated!
她瞳孔放大
没反射反应
No reflexes. We're not reading any brain activity.
看不到脑部活动
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
别这样 你快死了
Come on, you're dying!
你得立刻回到你的肉体 没时间了
You have to return to your body now. You don't have time.
时间是相对的
Time is relative.
你还不懂
Your body hasn't even hit the floor yet.
我花了这么多年
I've spent so many years...
窥探未来
Peering through time...
看着眼前这一刻
Looking at this exact moment.
但却看不透它
But I can't see past it.
我避开了无数可怕的未来
I've prevented countless, terrible futures.
每个未来之后总是有另一个
And after each one, there's always another.
它们全都导向这里
And they all lead here...
却不再往前
But never further.
你认为你的死期到了
You think this is where you die.
想知道我在你的未来看到什么吗？
You wonder what I see in your future?
不想
No.
想
Yes.
我始终没看到你的未来
I never saw your future.
只看到它的可能性
Only its possibilities.
你具有强大的行善能力
You have such a capacity for goodness.
你一向出类拔萃
You always excelled...
但不是因为你渴望成功
But not because you craved success...
而是你害怕失败
But because of your fear of failure.
所以我才成为一个杰出的医生
That's what made me a great doctor.
那正是阻止你更伟大的障碍
It's precisely what kept you from greatness.
傲慢与恐惧
Arrogance and fear still keep you...
依然让你无法学会
From learning the simplest and most significant lesson of all.
最简单最重要的教训
那是？
Which is?
重点不在你身上
It's not about you.
当你第一次来找我
When you first came to me...
你问我如何治愈强纳森潘柏恩
You asked me how I was able to heal Jonathan pangborn.
我没有
I didn't.
他将次元能量直接注入自己身体
He channels dimensional energy directly into his own body.
他利用法力让自己走路？
He uses magic to walk?
一直如此
Constantly.
他有选择
He had a choice...
重返自己的生活
To return to his own life...
或是追求比自己更大的目标
Or to serve something greater than himself.
所以我的手可以恢复正常？
So I could have my hands back again?
重拾过去的生活？
My old life?
可以
You could.
那么世界只会变得更悲惨
And the world would be all the lesser for it.
我厌恶从黑暗次元汲取能量
I've hated drawing power from the dark dimension.
但你很清楚
But as you well know...
有时必须打破陈规
Sometimes one must break the rules...
才能成就更远大的目标
In order to serve the greater good.
莫度可不会这么想
Mordo won't see it that way.
莫度的灵魂严谨而僵化
Mordo's soul is rigid and unmovable...
因为年轻时经历太多风雨
Forged by the fires of his youth.
他需要你的弹性
He needs your flexibility...
一如你需要他的定力
Just as you need his strength.
你们联手才有可能阻止多玛暮
Only together do you stand a chance of stopping dormammu.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready.
从来没有人准备好
No one ever is.
我们无法选择时机
We don't get to choose our time.
死亡赋予生命意义
Death is what gives life meaning.
让人知道日子有限
To know your days are numbered.
人生苦短
Your time is short.
你以为过了这么久 我应该准备好了
You'd think after all this time, I'd be ready.
但看看我
But look at me.
将一个时刻不断延长
Stretching one moment out into a thousand...
就为了赏雪
Just so that I can watch the snow.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我不懂到底是怎么一回事
I don't understand what's happening.
我知道
I know.
但我现在必须离开
But I have to go away now.
你说失去双手不是世界末日
You said that losing my hands didn't have to be the end.
反而可能是开始
That it could be a beginning.
是啊
Yeah.
因为还有其他方式可以救人
Because there are other ways to save lives.
更困难的方式
A harder way.
更奇怪的方式
A weirder way.
帕默医师请到急诊室…
Doctor Palmer to the er, please. Doctor Palmer to the er.
我不要你走
I don't want you to go.
别闹了
Stop!
香港
好好挑选武器
Choose your weapon wisely.
谁都别想进入这间至圣所
No one steps foot in this sanctum.
谁都不准
No one.
卡西流斯
Kaecilius.
你站在历史错误的一边 王
You're on the wrong side of history, wong.
她死了
She's dead.
你说得对
You were right.
她跟我想的不一样
She wasn't who I thought she was.
她很复杂
She was complicated.
复杂？
Complicated?
黑暗次元变化无常
The dark dimension is volatile.
危险
Dangerous.
要是它制伏了她呢？
What if it overtook her?
她教我们那是禁忌
She taught us it was forbidden...
自己却汲取它的能量 多活了几百年
While she drew on its power to steal centuries of life.
她只是在做她认为正确的事
She did what she thought was right.
不是不报 时候未到
The bill comes due.
你还不明白吗？
Don't you see?
她的过错导致狂热者效忠多玛暮
Her transgressions led the zealots to dormammu.
卡西流斯就是她的错
Kaecilius was her fault!
如今我们…
And here we are...
却得面对她欺骗世人的后果
In the consequence of her deception.
一个陷入混乱的世界
A world on fire.
莫度 伦敦至圣所已沦陷
Mordo, the London sanctum has fallen.
纽约两度遭受攻击
The New York one has been attacked twice.
你知道他们接下来的目标
You know where they're going next.
香港
Hong Kong.
你说过要拚命去对抗
You told me once to fight like my life depended on it...
因为有一天可能非生即死
Because one day, it might.
那就是今天
Well, today is that day.
我无法独力击败他们
I cannot defeat them alone.
至圣所已经沦陷了
The sanctum's already fallen.
黑暗次元
The dark dimension.
多玛暮来了
Dormammu is coming.
太迟了
It's too late.
什么都无法阻止他
Nothing can stop him.
不见得
Not necessarily.
不
No.
走吧
The spell's working.
我们还有第二次机会
We've got a second chance.
不
No!
王
Wong.
破坏自然法则 我了
Breaking the laws of nature. I know.
现在不能停
Well, don't stop now.
至圣所复原后
When the sanctum's restored, they'll attack it again.
他们会再攻击
We've got to defend it.
我们必须守护它
快点
Come on!
起来 史传奇
Get up, strange.
起来反抗
Get up and fight.
我们能打完这场仗
We can finish this.
你们反抗不了必然的结果
You can't fight the inevitable.
是不是很美？
Isn't it beautiful?
一个超越时间的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
超越时间 史传奇
Beyond time...
Strange.
他走了
He's gone.
就连史传奇都弃你而去 屈服在他的力量之下
Even strange has left you and surrendered to his power.
多玛暮 我是来找你商量的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你是来送死的
You've come to die.
你的世界现在是我的世界
Your world is now my world...
就像其他的世界一样
Like all worlds.
多玛暮 我是来找你商量的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你是来送死的
You've come to die.
你的世界现在是我的…
Your world is now my...
这是怎么搞的？
What is this?
幻觉？
Illusion?
不 这是真的
No. This is real.
很好
Good.
多玛暮 我是来找你商量的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你…怎么回事？
You've... what is happening?
就像你把你次元的法力 给了卡西流斯
Just as you gave kaecilius powers from your dimension...
我也从我的次元带来一点法力
I brought a little power from mine.
这是时间
This is time.
无限循环的时间
Endless looped time.
你敢！
You dare!
多玛暮 我是来找你商量的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你不能永远来这套
You cannot do this forever.
其实我可以
Actually, I can.
现在情况就是如此
This is how things are now.
你和我困在这一刻里
You and me, trapped in this moment...
无止尽
Endlessly.
那么你会不断死亡
Then you will spend eternity dying.
对 但地球上的人都能活命
Yes. But everyone on earth will live.
但你会受苦
But you will suffer.
痛苦是我的老朋友
Pain's an old friend.
多玛暮
Dormammu...
我是来找你商量的
I've come to bargain.
赶快停止
End this!
多玛暮… 多玛暮
Dormammu... dormammu...
Dormammu...
你不可能赢的
You will never win.
没错
No...
但我可以输
But I can lose...
一而再…
Again and again...
再而三
And again...
一直重复下去
And again, forever.
那样你就成了我的囚犯
And that makes you my prisoner.
不
No!
住手
Stop!
赶快停止
Make this stop!
还我自由
Set me free!
不
No.
我是来找你商量的
I've come to bargain.
你想怎样？
What do you want?
带着你的狂热者离开地球
Take your zealots from the earth.
停止攻击我的世界
End your assault on my world.
永远别再回来
Never come back.
只要照做
Do it...
我就中止这循环
And I'll break the loop.
起来 史传奇
Get up, strange!
起来反抗
Get up and fight.
我们能打完这场仗
We can finish this.
是不是很美？
Isn't it beautiful?
一个超越时间的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
你做了什么？
What have you done?
我跟他打了个商量
I made a bargain.
这是什么？
What is this?
你所要的一切
Well, it's everything you've ever wanted.
陪着多玛暮永生不死
Eternal life as part of the one.
你不会喜欢的
You're not gonna like it.
你真该偷走整本书才对
Yeah, you know, you really should have stolen
the whole book because the warnings...
因为警语在咒语后面
The warnings come after the spells.
真搞笑
That's funny.
我们成功了
We did it.
对
Yes.
我们成功了
Yes, we did it.
同时也违反了…
By also violating...
自然法则
The natural law.
看看你四周 结束了
Look around you. It's over.
你还以为不会有后果吗？
You still think there will be no consequences, strange?
不必付出代价？
No price to pay?
我们破坏了规则 跟她一样
We broke our rules, just like her.
不是不报 时候未到
The bill comes due.
绝无例外
Always!
迟早都要还
A reckoning.
我不愿再走这条路
I will follow this path no longer.
好
Yeah, okay.
明智的抉择
Wise choice.
你会戴上阿迦莫多之眼
You'll wear the eye of agamotto...
当你能完全掌握它的力量
Once you've mastered its powers.
在那之前
Until then...
最好不要戴着无限宝石逛大街
Best not to walk the streets wearing an infinity stone.
什么石？
A what?
就算你有秘术的天赋
You might have a gift for the mystic arts,
但要学的还多着呢
but you still have much to learn.
古一的死讯将传遍多重宇宙
Word of the ancient one's death will spread through the multiverse.
没有至尊魔法师能扞卫地球
Earth has no sorcerer supreme to defend it.
我们必须做好准备
We must be ready.
我们会的
We'll be ready.
导演 斯科特·德瑞克森
编剧 斯科特·德瑞克森 斯科特·德瑞克森  C·罗伯特·凯尔吉尔
制片人 凯文·费吉
执行制片人 路易斯·路易斯·斯波西托
执行制片人 维多利亚·阿隆索
执行制片人 斯蒂芬·布鲁萨德
执行制片人 查尔斯·尼沃斯 斯坦·李
联合制片人 戴维·J·格兰特
根据 斯坦·李和史蒂夫·迪特寇 漫画原着改编
摄影指导 本·戴维斯
美术指导 查尔斯·伍德
剪辑 怀特·史密斯 萨布瑞娜·普利斯科
服装设计 亚历山大·布莱恩
视觉特效总监 斯蒂芬·切克蒂
视觉特效制片人 苏珊·皮克特
音乐 迈克·吉亚奇诺
音乐制作人 达夫·乔丹
选角导演 莎拉·哈莉·费恩
本尼迪克特·康伯巴奇
切瓦特·埃加福特
瑞秋·麦克亚当斯
本尼迪克特·王
迈克尔·斯图巴
本杰明·布拉特
斯科特·阿特金斯
以及 麦斯·米科尔森
以及 蒂尔达·斯文顿
漫威电影公司 荣誉出品
奇异博士
Doctor strange
所以地球现在有巫师了？
so earth has wizards now, huh?
喝茶吗？
Tea?
我不喝茶
I don't drink tea.
那你都喝什么？
What do you drink?
不喝茶
Not tea.
我有一份名单
So, I keep a watch list...
都是来自其他世界
Of individuals and beings from other realms
可能对这世界构成威胁的人物
that may be a threat to this world.
令弟洛基就是其中之一
Your adopted brother, loki, is one of those beings.
值得将他列入
Worthy inclusion.
是啊
Yeah.
为什么带他来纽约？
So why bring him here to New York?
说来话长
It's a bit of a long story.
简直像在演八点档
Family drama, that kind of thing.
我们在找我们的父亲
But we're looking for my father.
了解 如果你们找到奥丁
Oh, okay. So if you found Odin...
就会立即回到阿斯嘉？
You'd all return to asgard promptly?
对 马上走
Oh, yes. Promptly.
太好了
Great!
容我协助你
Allow me to help you.
3D特效字幕制作 稚园老
有事吗？
Can I help you?
他们用担架把你抬进卡玛泰姬
They carried you into kamar-taj on a stretcher.
如今看看你 潘柏恩
Look at you now, pangborn.
莫度
Mordo.
有何贵干 兄弟？
So what can I do for you, man?
我离开了很久
I've been away for many months now, and I've had a revelation.
得到一个启示
魔法师真正的目的
The true purpose of a sorcerer...
是扭曲事物原本的样貌
Is to twist things out of their proper shape...
偷取能量
Stealing power...
破坏自然
Perverting nature.
就像你
Like you.
我没偷走任何东西 这是我的法力
I've stolen nothing. This is my power.
我的 法力…
Mine.
Power...
都有目的
Has a purpose.
你为何要这么做？
Why are you doing this?
因为我终于看见这世界的问题
Because I see, at long last, what's wrong with the world.
魔法师太多了
Too many sorcerers.
敬请期待奇异博士归来
\h漫\h威\h\h\h电影工作室 _______
代理发行 华特·迪士尼电影公司\h\h